hello and welcome to the grow Your Life
podcast my name is jeremi Kowski in this
podcast I talk about ways for you to
grow in your life and your business to
make more money if you are a coach
course creator or Mentor what I want to
talk about here today is beating
procrastination especially when we don't
feel ready to do something how many of
y'all feel that way I know what it's
like because I have experienced this for
years myself in fact even before I
recorded this podcast I was like oh I'm
not ready yet I don't know what I want
to talk about and it happens to me daily
with almost every task that I have to do
if I let it defeat me I can take weeks
or even months between doing the things
that I need to do and that's where I
find that a lot of people are in their
businesses is that they end up doing
that and so here's what I do to help me
with this and I hope that you find some
wisdom and what I'm about to share
because in our businesses we only get
what we prioritize what is important to
us and the truth is is that it's nothing
to beat ourselves up over it's nothing
to get angry at ourselves over it's just
that other stuff is more important and
that's the truth is that other stuff is
often times more important you know this
week I had some different stuff going on
with my family that were important that
we had to take care of that I had to do
had to put off some different things
that was important I don't want to go
out there and be this guy that just says
well my business is more important so my
family takes a second seat no that's not
what I'm talking about what I want to do
is I want to make sure that I'm the one
in control of my life and that I'm not
letting my feelings control what I'm
doing and that's where we want to get to
often times when we don't feel ready to
do something because it doesn't feel
right we end up letting it sit on the
back burner and we don't even notice it
and the worst part is is that we can do
this for months and months and months at
a time and think that we're making
progress and so the way out of this is
to actually take a look at what am I
actually getting done that's moving the
needle forward for me in my business in
my goals and I have a thing I call it
the law of 14 days not taking longer
than about 14 days and re-eval valuating
okay how much progress did I make in
that 14 days time were there certain
behaviors that I had were there certain
situations that came up I had a
situation with a with a client that I
was working with that completely
derailed some of my confidence and it
was a situation that was related to
something that used to happened to me
years ago that hasn't come up in a long
time and I had to say whoa okay people
pleasing has gotten the best of me again
thought I had beaten that boss but now I
got to do it again and I go got to go
after it and I can't let it beat me and
so one of the best things that you can
do when you feel like procrastinating
when you feel like you're not ready to
do something is break it down into
smaller steps and just get started on
one step one of the things that I do
especially when I'm procrastinating on
recording content or writing sales copy
or or editing a landing page or writing
an email or any number of the things
that we do in our business that we're
like oh I just don't feel ready yet to
do is I just start doing it and you
might say well if I don't know how to do
it what don't I start doing you're
overthinking it way too hard start the
action like I'm talking about move your
body physically to open up the program
on your computer open up the camera open
up the recorder start recording press
record and here's the cool part about it
you can delete it later you can get rid
of it if it didn't work you can throw it
aside you know last week I was recording
a course and I had to record three times
because I kept stumbling over my words
but I'm telling you the third time I did
it it came out great and it was awesome
I was too caught up in my head the first
couple of
takes and you know years ago I used to
then beat myself up and I wasn't ready
and it took me hours to get ready as far
as that goes no just move on
quickly see yourself a vision of
yourself doing the thing that you're
stuck doing start imagining in your mind
that you're actually doing that thing
that you're stuck doing so like this
podcast episode right here right before
I was about to record it I had like
three or four podcast ideas okay and
this one was actually the best one
because I was like I'll wait a sec I got
a great in the moment example to give
people for
this I was like oh what am I talking
about oh it's 4:30 oh we got to go we
got to be somewhere in an
hour baby's taking a nap so this is a
great time for me to record a podcast oh
but this couch feels
comfortable and literally I did that for
like 10 minutes
okay and then I was like you know what
I'm going to go sit in this chair and
I'm going to press record and we're
going to start it we're going to start
getting getting going and I can tell you
that that
behavior of just getting it
going starting the
process I've been recording for what
five minutes it's coming out great I
think this podcast is one of the best
ones I've ever done in fact because I
started to take action and I took action
and I did the thing that I knew that I
wanted to do now before I stepped into
it I saw myself recording a podcast
confidently I knew the Baseline of what
I was going to talk about I picked
something I knew there were five other
ideas that I had but I I went after it
and I chose to do one of those ideas not
being worried if the other five ideas
don't
happen and then I started doing the
thing that I needed to do pressing
record starting to talk starting to
communicate and I can tell you in my
career in my business over the years
whenever I've done that things have gone
really really well for me they've worked
out well they've come together overall
in the way that I want them to and
whenever I've sat around and I've said
oh I'm I'm not sure if I'm ready yet I'm
not sure if I feel ready yet I've
struggled with that and we can get so
caught up and even trying to analyze why
we're procrastinating often times times
is because we feel uncomfortable can I
tell you this in business you're going
to feel uncomfortable in most of the
stuff that you got to do that you got to
do that you got to
do but by doing it while you feel
uncomfortable while you feel scared
while you feel
nervous not being worried am I going to
bombit am I going to say everything
perfect is it going to come out perfect
and also by the way believing that
you're actually going to do it well
actually getting your mind to believe
that taking action in something starting
something is actually the right way to
do it not over planning not overthinking
not overanalyzing not having all the
pieces figured out but being willing to
just get started with
something to put yourself out there
publicly to get it going and the other
thing too is get some help get some
support in some of the things that maybe
you're a little bit stuck
on maybe you're wondering about an idea
or two call up a friend talk out some
things well not not that friend that's
negative all the time but one that you
can talk through and process things with
or or in my coaching program we have
people you can literally bring your
content your courses your ideas all
those things no matter what you're doing
throughout the day into our program and
ask questions about it and I'm there my
our group is there to help you along the
way the the reason we procrastinate is
because there's some kind of discomfort
that we're trying to avoid and we're not
sure what's going to happen and I can I
tell you this the more often you just
don't let that thing stop you see if see
what happens is we actually create habit
Frameworks in us if I have a habit of
I'm going to get started and I'm going
to constantly procrastinate on this
thing it becomes 10 times harder the
next time to do that thing that we
procrastinated on I notic this in the
gym I noticed this with healthy e
I noticed this in my
business and what it is is that we end
up literally creating our own world of
excuses and reasons why we can't do the
thing oh I'm not ready yet I don't know
if this this software is ready yet I
heard somebody say they haven't built
their site because they're waiting for a
feature to come on some software that's
out there when there's 10 other
softwares that are out there they could
have built something on can I tell you
this we can always come up with reasons
to delay the inevit
of what we need to
do the hard work of when it comes to
business is taking action on the stuff
that you know that you should do but
you're not ready yet to do and you're
not even sure how it's going to turn out
and quite frankly your brain is coming
up with all the ways it could go wrong
and yet you still do it
anyways to put yourself out
there and I and I stand before you here
today listen I tell you I probably have
done I do a lot better at this than most
people but I fail every day at it at the
same time I'm consistent all the time
with building my business with getting
stuff going with creating the stuff that
I want to create in my business and yet
at the same time I fail every single day
and procrastinate and I got to pick
myself up intentionally each day it's
like brushing your teeth you don't brush
your teeth just once you do it again and
again and again like your
health and that's what it is is that a
healthy business owner is consistent and
they learn to create habits that are
consistent you know it's interesting I
was reading the book Atomic habits it's
actually a really really great book I
resisted this book for a long time I
thought it was silly for some reason I
thought it was silly and then I read it
like a couple weeks ago and I was like
my goodness this one of the best books
that's out there is that our brain
creates these little habits when it call
when it talks about Atomic habits I
thought it was like an atomic bomb like
really big habits I was like G gosh no
it's about the little things that you do
that compound over time the little stuff
if you're just 1% better each day with
your habits that's going to compound to
100% better after four
months again and again and again that
process these aren't just arbitrary
numbers this is
reality and so when you can look at okay
what behaviors am I doing what is the
little triggers what are the things that
I'm feeling
internally we start to take account for
what those are and then we have a
habitual action that we do when those
things come up you know for the longest
time I was struggling in my in my house
in my daily life to get things organized
and stuff like that because I had a
habit of letting my feelings take over
my actions and we do this naturally all
of us do
this if your business if you haven't
launched it if you don't have leads
coming in your business and you're not
selling to people every single week in
your business to get more clients there
are habits that you are procrastinating
on that have taken over that you need to
start to take account for start to
become accountable to yourself and maybe
have an accountability partner like in a
coaching program for to help you with
this one of the things that we help you
with inside of my accelerator program is
to hold you
accountable for the things that you have
committed to do listen I know that you
can accomplish your goals and listen I
know when you go out there sometimes
things don't go the way that we want
sometimes they fail sometimes things
don't work out but the more resilient
you get develop a resiliency
habit where when things don't go how you
want you changed your
reaction it's okay I'm going to get back
up again you know today my day today
didn't go how I wanted it to it happened
I can give you a thousand reasons why it
it had to go the way that it did but it
didn't go how I
wanted and I for a split second I got
into complaining and whining and feeling
frustrated that my day didn't go how I
wanted it to bless God why I did not go
how I wanted it
to and then I realized is that helping
nobody no it's not but it's an addiction
that I had to that feeling of
complaining we become addicted to our
excuses and our should dos
and we often justify it as a spirit of
Excellence
even when in fact it's just breaking it
down smaller steps what's that thing
that I've been putting off what's that
thing that I need to take action on that
I need to get started on that I need to
stop putting off putting off putting off
and start moving the needle forward in
my life to start to see things come
together for me when you can do
this you start to see the results come
in like wild fire and it's amazing what
ends up happening when we do this my
friends I'm excited for
you and I want you some of you might
need to re relisten to this every day
for three
days in the morning and even at night
it's short enough 13 minutes long start
to get you motivated to start to get you
realizing that and here's one of the
things that I like to do before bed that
helps me with my habits I take a look
and I say okay tomorrow this is what I'm
going to do and in the morning I think
think about this is what didn't work
yesterday it didn't work yesterday for
me to worry about this situation it
didn't work for me yesterday for me to
complain about this situation it didn't
work for me yesterday to sit around for
an hour until I felt like doing the
thing that I needed to do I just got to
get started with it I just got to take
action with it I just got to do the
thing and start to see things come
together for me
and I'll tell you you know
what every time I do that things start
coming together real well for me and
anytime I'm waiting to feel good enough
for it to happen listen I get it
sometimes we just don't feel good
enough that's when I'll go do something
else I'll go distract myself for a
little bit to start to feel better and
then I'll come back to it and and if
that doesn't work then I'm going to say
okay what's happening what am I trying
to avoid what's internally the struggle
that's going you might not find it right
now
today it might take you a week to figure
it out it might take you 3 days to
figure it out for me it's about two to
three days as I'll be like okay what's
going on here and about 3 days later I
figure out what's actually really going
on beneath the
surface and so listen life happens
things happen we are on a constant
journey of growth to become better today
than we were yesterday I believe in you
and I know that you can do this this and
I know that you can accomplish anything
that you want
to but you got to choose to take action
even when it doesn't feel good even when
you don't feel ready even when it
doesn't feel like the right
timing that's where the beauty and Magic
happens in life all right listen share
this with somebody don't hold this to
yourself if you know somebody who maybe
is struggling to have the kind of life
that they want help them see what I've
shared in this video share this podcast
with episode with them help them to see
what's going on and I want to help you
reach your goals in my accelerator
program we work with our clients every
single week to reach their goals to help
them get more clients and their coaching
business to help them sell more of their
coaching programs and their courses
their mentorship and I'd love to help
you as well to get unstuck to start to
make the kind of cash flow that you want
in your business my name is Jer mikowski
this is the grow Life podcast we'll talk
sooner have a good one
[Music]